Guide to the Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
5488 B
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
669 linear feet.
Correspondence, Rule books, Agreements, etc.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
Subjects:
Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States--Sources.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted. Please contact the Kheel Center Reference Archivist for access information.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This forms a portion of collection #5488 B. The guide to the entire collection is available here.
Series XLIX is arranged in 39 sub-series by Union file number.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series XLIX. GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - Sub-Series 310-0. General Correspondence
    - Congressional Endorsements., 1966 (Box 496, Folder 1)
      April-August 1966.
    - Congressional Endorsements., 1965-1966 (Box 496, Folder 2)
      November 1965-March 1966.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1956-1959 (Box 496, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1953-1955 (Box 496, Folder 4)
      June 1953-55.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1952-1953 (Box 496, Folder 5)
      February 1952-May 1953.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1950-1952 (Box 496, Folder 6)
      November 1950-January 1952.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1949-1950 (Box 496, Folder 7)
      October 1949-October 1950.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1949 (Box 496, Folder 8)
      June-September 1949.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1948-1949 (Box 496, Folder 9)
      October 1948-May 1949.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1948 (Box 496, Folder 10)
      May-September 1948.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1947-1948 (Box 497, Folder 1)
      1947-April 1948.
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1945-1946 (Box 497, Folder 2)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1944 (Box 497, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1942-1943 (Box 497, Folder 4)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1934-1941 (Box 497, Folder 5)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1942 (Box 497, Folder 6)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1943 (Box 497, Folder 7)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1938 (Box 497, Folder 8)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1936 (Box 497, Folder 9)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1946 (Box 497, Folder 10)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1946-1947 (Box 497, Folder 11)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1944 (Box 497, Folder 12)
    - Congressional Endorsements. General, 1947 (Box 497, Folder 13)
    - Congressional Endorsements. Committee of National Legislative Representatives, 1942 (Box 497, Folder 14)
    - Congressional Endorsements. Committee of National Legislative Representatives, 1946 (Box 497, Folder 15)
    - Congressional Endorsements. Committee of National Legislative Representatives, 1944 (Box 497, Folder 16)
    - Congressional Endorsements. Committee of National Legislative Representatives, 1940 (Box 498, Folder 1)
    - Congressional Endorsements. Committee of National Legislative Representatives, 1938 (Box 498, Folder 2)
    - Congressional Endorsements. Committee of National Legislative Representatives. General Elections, 1934 (Box 498, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Endorsements. Committee of National Legislative Representatives. Primary Elections, 1934 (Box 498, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series 310-7. General Correspondence
    - United States Department of Labor, 1929 (Box 498, Folder 5)
      1929 March 1
  - Sub-Series 310-26. General Correspondence
    - History of Labor, 1922 (Box 498, Folder 6)
      May-June 1922.
  - Sub-Series 310-45. General Correspondence
    - United States Department of Labor. Womens' Bureau, 1922 (Box 498, Folder 7)
      August 10-, 1922.
  - Sub-Series 310-88. General Correspondence
    - Request for Railroad Transportation, 1923 (Box 498, Folder 8)
      September-October 1923.
  - Sub-Series 310-101. General Correspondence
    - University of Minnesota, 1924 (Box 498, Folder 9)
      February 2-9, 1924.
  - Sub-Series 310-104. General Correspondence
    - Canadian Labour Party, 1924 (Box 498, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 310-118. General Correspondence
    - Community Chest. General, 1934-1947 (Box 498, Folder 11)
    - Community Chest. General, 1937-1945 (Box 498, Folder 12)
    - Community Chest. Cincinnati, Ohio, 1924 (Box 498, Folder 13)
      1924 May 5
  - Sub-Series 310-239. General Correspondence
    - Who's Who. American Labor, 1925 (Box 498, Folder 14)
    - Who's Who in America, 1950 (Box 498, Folder 15)
    - American Labor Who's Who, 1924 (Box 498, Folder 16)
      1924 November 6
  - Sub-Series 310-269. General Correspondence
    - Negro Workers' Trade Union Committee, 1925 (Box 498, Folder 17)
      November-December 1925.
  - Sub-Series 310-297. General Correspondence
    - Princeton University, 1930 (Box 498, Folder 18)
    - Princeton University, 1929 (Box 498, Folder 19)
      October 14-17, 1929.
    - Princeton University, 1927-1928 (Box 498, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series 310-307. General Correspondence
    - Northwestern University, 1938 (Box 498, Folder 21)
    - Northwestern University, 1933 (Box 498, Folder 22)
    - Northwestern University, 1927-1928 (Box 498, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series 310-332. General Correspondence
    - University of Cincinnati, 1929 (Box 498, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series 310-376. General Correspondence
    - University of California, 1930 (Box 498, Folder 25)
  - Sub-Series 310-384. General Correspondence
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1930 (Box 498, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series 310-404. General Correspondence
    - Independent Labour Party of Canada, 1931 (Box 498, Folder 27)
  - Sub-Series 310-407. General Correspondence
    - University of Wisconsin, 1931 (Box 498, Folder 28)
  - Sub-Series 310-414. General Correspondence
    - University of Virginia, 1931 (Box 498, Folder 29)
  - Sub-Series 310-456. General Correspondence
    - University of Chicago, 1933-1934 (Box 498, Folder 30)
  - Sub-Series 310-609. General Correspondence
    - Radio Broadcasts, 1952-1959 (Box 498, Folder 31)
      May 1952-59.
    - Radio Broadcasts, 1946-1952 (Box 498, Folder 32)
      1946-April 1952.
    - Radio Broadcasts, 1940-1945 (Box 498, Folder 33)
    - Radio Broadcasts. Edwards, F., 1952-1954 (Box 498, Folder 34)
    - Radio Broadcasts. National Broadcasting Company, 1946-1947 (Box 498, Folder 35)
    - Radio Broadcasts. Labor for Victory Program, 1944 (Box 498, Folder 36)
    - Radio Broadcasts. Labor for Victory Program, 1942-1943 (Box 498, Folder 37)
    - Radio Broadcasts, 1943-1946 (Box 498, Folder 38)
    - Radio Broadcasts, 1941 (Box 498, Folder 39)
  - Sub-Series 310-612. General Correspondence
    - American Red Cross, 1944-1950 (Box 499, Folder 1)
    - American Red Cross, 1942-1943 (Box 499, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Series 310-614. General Correspondence
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1957-1958 (Box 499, Folder 3)
      February 1957-January 1958.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1956-1957 (Box 499, Folder 4)
      February 1956-January 1957.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1954-1956 (Box 499, Folder 5)
      September 1954-January 1956.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1953-1954 (Box 499, Folder 6)
      November 1953-August 1954.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1952-1953 (Box 499, Folder 7)
      August 1952-October 1953.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1951-1952 (Box 499, Folder 8)
      February 1951-July 1952.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1949-1951 (Box 499, Folder 9)
      September 1949-January 1951.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1948-1949 (Box 499, Folder 10)
      1948-August 1949.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1946-1947 (Box 499, Folder 11)
      July 1946-June 1947.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1944-1946 (Box 499, Folder 12)
      1944-June 1946.
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan, 1942-1943 (Box 499, Folder 13)
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan. Report of Sommerfield, C.F., Fellow, 1946-1947 (Box 499, Folder 14)
    - Harvard University Scholarship Trade Union Fellowship Plan. Annual Report, 1946-1947 (Box 499, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series 310-627. General Correspondence
    - Who's Who in Labor, 1945-1956 (Box 500, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 310-628. General Correspondence
    - Speech Material, 1957-1958 (Box 500, Folder 2)
      March 1957-February 1958.
    - Speech Material, 1954-1957 (Box 500, Folder 3)
      1954-February 1957.
    - Speech Material, 1950-1953 (Box 500, Folder 4)
    - Speech Material, 1950-1951 (Box 500, Folder 5)
    - Speech Material, 1947-1949 (Box 500, Folder 6)
      November 1947-December 1949.
    - Speech Material, 1945-1947 (Box 500, Folder 7)
      1945-October 1947.
  - Sub-Series 310-629. General Correspondence
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1954-1957 (Box 500, Folder 8)
      March 16, 1954-May 22, 1957.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1953-1954 (Box 500, Folder 9)
      September 1953-March 15, 1954.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1953 (Box 500, Folder 10)
      April 1953-August 1953.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1952-1953 (Box 500, Folder 11)
      December 1952-March 1953.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1952 (Box 500, Folder 12)
      August-November 1952.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1952 (Box 500, Folder 13)
      April-July 1952.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1947-1952 (Box 501, Folder 1)
      January 1947-March 1952.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1946 (Box 501, Folder 2)
      July-December 1946.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1945-1946 (Box 501, Folder 3)
      November 1945-June 1946.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1945 (Box 501, Folder 4)
      August-October 1945.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1945 (Box 501, Folder 5)
      May 26, 1945-July 1945.
    - Information for General Chairmen, 1945 (Box 501, Folder 6)
      March 19, 1945-May 25, 1945.
  - Sub-Series 310-630. General Correspondence
    - President Harry S. Truman, 1945-1951 (Box 501, Folder 7)
    - President Harry S. Truman. Addresses and Statements, 1935-1945 (Box 501, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 310-635. General Correspondence
    - Moral Rearmament, 1953-1956 (Box 501, Folder 9)
      July 1953-56.
    - Moral Rearmament, 1950-1953 (Box 501, Folder 10)
      July 1950-June 1953.
    - Moral Rearmament, 1942-1950 (Box 501, Folder 11)
      1942-June 1950.
    - Moral Rearmament, 1940-1941 (Box 502, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 310-643. General Correspondence
    - Foundation of Catholics for Human Brotherhood, 1947-1948 (Box 502, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Series 310-645. General Correspondence
    - American Cancer Society, 1947-1956 (Box 502, Folder 3)
      March 25, 1947-56.
  - Sub-Series 310-650. General Correspondence
    - American Heart Association, 1949-1953 (Box 502, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series 310-652. General Correspondence
    - Diorama Exhibit. Trades and Labour Congress of Canada; Windsor, Ontario, Canada, 1955 (Box 502, Folder 5)
      1955 May 31
    - Diorama Exhibit. Canadian Labour Congress; Toronto, Ontario, Canada, 1956 (Box 502, Folder 5)
      1956 April 23
    - Diorama Exhibit. ECA Showings in Germany, 1950-1956 (Box 502, Folder 6)
    - Diorama Exhibit. Mattoon, Illinois, 1955 (Box 502, Folder 7)
      September 4-10, 1955.
    - Diorama Exhibit. J.L. Brandeis and Sons, Omaha, Nebraska, 1955 (Box 502, Folder 8)
      January 24-29, 1955.
    - Diorama Exhibit. Omaha Centennial Celebration, Omaha, Nebraska, 1954 (Box 502, Folder 9)
      October 24-November 28, 1954.
    - Diorama Exhibit. Nebraska State Fair, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1954 (Box 502, Folder 10)
      September 5-10, 1954.
    - Diorama Exhibit. Boston, Massachusetts. Claim, 1952 (Box 502, Folder 11)
      1952 May
    - Diorama Exhibit. Kansas Free Fair, Topeka, Kansas, 1952 (Box 502, Folder 12)
      September 6-12, 1952.
    - Diorama Exhibit. General, 1948-1949 (Box 502, Folder 13)
      1948-July 1949.
    - Diorama Exhibit. Texas State Fair, Dallas, Texas, 1949 (Box 502, Folder 14)
      October 8-28, 1949.
    - Diorama Exhibit. Cincinnati Gas and Electric Building, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1949 (Box 502, Folder 15)
      December 1-31, 1949.
    - Diorama Exhibit. General, 1950-1952 (Box 502, Folder 16)
      March 1950-July 1952.
    - Diorama Exhibit. General, 1949-1950 (Box 502, Folder 17)
      August 1949-February 1950.
  - Sub-Series 310-656. General Correspondence
    - American Heritage Foundation -September 1947-July 1949 (Box 503, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 310-663. General Correspondence
    - National Association of Railway Business Women, 1950-1957 (Box 503, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Series 310-673. General Correspondence
    - United Railroad Operating Crafts, 1957-1958 (Box 503, Folder 3)
      November 1957-August 21, 1958.
    - United Railroad Operating Crafts, 1957 (Box 503, Folder 4)
      April-October 1957.
    - United Railroad Operating Crafts, 1956-1957 (Box 503, Folder 5)
      April 1956-March 1957.
    - United Railroad Operating Crafts, 1955-1956 (Box 503, Folder 6)
      October 1955-March 1956.
    - United Railroad Operating Crafts, 1955 (Box 503, Folder 7)
      January-September 1955.
    - United Railroad Operating Crafts, 1951-1954 (Box 503, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 310-676. General Correspondence
    - Council Against Communist Aggression, 1951-1954 (Box 503, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 310-680. General Correspondence
    - Harry S. Truman Library, Inc., 1953-1954 (Box 503, Folder 10)
      October 1953-June 1954.
    - Harry S. Truman Library, Inc., 1952-1953 (Box 503, Folder 11)
      1952-September 1953.
  - Sub-Series 310-684. General Correspondence
    - Negro Labor Committee, USA, 1952-1957 (Box 503, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 310-687. General Correspondence
    - Arthritis and Rheumatism Foundation, 1953-1956 (Box 503, Folder 13)
      1953-June 1956.
    - Arthritis and Rheumatism Foundation, 1956-1957 (Box 504, Folder 1)
      July 1956-57.
  - Sub-Series 310-692. General Correspondence
    - Southern Crafts, Inc., 1956-1957 (Box 504, Folder 2)